LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

SUMMARY

Dedicated IT professional with extensive customer service, technical training and management, and project managing experience with expertise in web development and network administration and desire to learn new things. Discipline in the following:

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API, JSON, SQL, SASS

Tools: Git/GitHub, Gulp, NPM, Node.js, MySQL, NoSQL, Heroku, Firebase

Libraries/Frameworks: Bootstrap, Express, REACT, jQuery, MongoDB, Backbone, Knockout

Software: Visual Studio, MS Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook & Visio, Adobe Photoshop & Acrobat

Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, UNIX, Linux, Cisco

PROJECTS

Common Ground | Firebase, JavaScript, APIs | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds Live https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds

Web app that provides a centralized location for a group of people to meet and provide suggestions for places to meet.

- Incorporates Firebase Authentication for users to login by email and password and stores login information in Realtime Database.
- Integrates a GeoLocator API that determines a centralize location using the city and state of each person and a Zomato API that allows the user to search by keyword for a place to meet at that location (i.e., restaurant, bar, etc.).

MeVite | MySQL, Node.js, Express | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/MeVite Live https://mevite.herokuapp.com/

Web app that allows users to create events and sends email to people the user has invited for attendance.

- Incorporates Passport.js for use user registration and authenit ation by saving user information in a Sequelize database.
- Integrates NPM packages nodemailer to send invites via email and bcryptjs to encrypt password data in the database when user registers.
- The app saves the event information and contacts in the database for tracking attendance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AT&T, Piscataway, NJ

VPN Technical Manager, October 2015 - May 2019

Issued and monitored activation of VPN service for high profile customers such as Bank of Montreal. Led online training for domestic new hires who were managing the installation and activation of VPN with BVOIP service.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my orders activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% with overseas team.

MIS/BVOIP Technical Manager, April 2010 - October 2015

Managed MIS and BVOIP ordering teams located overseas in the Philippines where my team worked on large projects for Panera Bread and J.C. Penney. Provided in-person training and onboarding support at overseas office. Developed and updated training documentation and assisted with support for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

• Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

New Hire Trainer / Process Engineer, September 2008 - April 2010

Trained new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ, May 2019 – Present Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ, Sept 1993 – May 1997

CERTIFICATIONS

Front-End Web Developer, Udacity	2015
Six-Sigma Green Belt	2009
Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA)	2004